NILAY MAZUMDER (1) Featured

Software Engineer, Requirement Gathering, Application Development, Requirement Analysis, Application Programming, Web Development, Java, J2EE, Spring, AWS cloud, oracle SQL, Unix, HTML, CSS, javaScript, Algorithm, Data structure, Datamining, Python, Django



Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Designation: Senior Associate

Current Company: TIAA Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: M.Tech [Computers]

Pref. Location: Hyderabad, Bengaluru / Bangalore, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Requirement Gathering, Application

Development, Requirement Analysis, Web Development, Java, Oracle PL-SQL, SOAP Web

Service, J2EE, Hibernate, SOAP, Spring

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 24-Nov-20 Last Modified: 24-Nov-20

Summary

Total Work Experience is nearly 5 years. Currently, working as a Technology Analyst in HSBC, Pune. Have prior Work experience with Siemens R&D, Tech Mahindra.

Current position as a Software Engineer in the Telecom Billing Department, posted in Kolkata.

Worked on Design/Development/Maintenance and Testing Projects across U.K and Middle-East.

3 years of professional experience in IT industry viz. Telecom, Web Design and Development.

Functional experience - Telecom Billing, RBM 5.3, Requirement analysis, Development & managing project plans, Build Management, Live issue debugging, Service request maintenance, Live deployment, DR deployment, client handling. Worked remotely with onshore/offshore teams, clients and vendors to meet client needs, commitment to delivery and Maintaining SLAs.

hands-on development and support in Telecom Billing domain, Java, ORACLE- PLSQL, RBM/Geneva COTs & UNIX.

Work Experience

TIAA as Senior Associate Nov 2020 to Till Date

development

HSBC as Senior Associate Java Jul 2019 to Nov 2020

Working as lead of CMB Surveillance project. Tracking live issues, providing L1, L2, L3 support Creating pipelines for automation Creating infrastructure for Power BI, SAS through AppDynamics Hands working on Cloud technologies, Java, Python Aspired Data Scientist

Siemens Industry Software as Technology Analyst Jul 2018 to Jul 2019

Working as a lead on Polarion ALM tool (Polarion Software owned by Siemens) which is hosted into AWS cloud. Here making infrastructure ready for the customer for deploying Polarion ALM along with customization, issue resolving, customer support, customer meeting, product development call handled day-to-day basis. Some of the customers are: ERT, MATTEL, GoGo Aviation, NSG, Ricardo Rail, Danfoss etc.

TechMahindra as Software Developer

May 2014 to May 2018

Current position as a Software Engineer in the Telecom Billing Department, posted in Kolkata.

Worked on Design/Development/Maintenance and Testing Projects across U.K and Middle-East.

4 years of professional experience in IT industry viz. Telecom, Web Design and Development.

Functional experience - Telecom Billing, RBM 5.3, Requirement analysis, Development & managing project plans, Build Management, Live issue debugging, Service request maintenance, Live deployment, DR deployment, client handling. Worked remotely with onshore/offshore teams, clients and vendors to meet client needs, commitment to delivery and Maintaining SLAs.

hands-on development and support in Telecom Billing domain, Java, J2EE, Hibernate, ORACLE- PLSQL, Webservice SOAP Rest, RBM/Geneva COTs & UNIX.

Resolved the Complicated Issues across E2E Environments, Productions to ensure speedy resolution.

Professional, dedicated, highly motivated, follow project standards and a good team player.

TechMahindra as software Engineer

May 2014 to May 2014

software development

Tech Mahindra Ltd. as Software Engineer- Application Programming

May 2014 to Nov 2017

Mar2017 - Sep2017: BP Billing ASM FP A

Client: British Telecommunications, UK

Work Location: London, Milton Keynes, United Kingdom

Component name: Antillia. It is a billing system. Here monthly billing, debt, rating, tariff, prices everything getting

calculated for business customers (eg. Big corporations like Santander Bank etc.).

Technology: Oracle 11g PL/SQL, Unix, Shell Scripting, Excel, RBM

Role: Application Support and Maintenance (Issue debug, issue resolve, service request restoration on the basis of urgency, live deployment, DR deployment, testing, client handling, client meeting, client requirement understanding on limited timeframe)

Responsibilities:

Customer/business meeting attending Live issue meeting attending On live Deployment of deliverables Dress rehearsals performing L1 L2 L3 support provision 24*7 on live billing engine (System Monitor) monitoring

Designation: Business Analyst

March 2016 - Feb2017: UKB-Antillia-Development

Client: British Telecommunications, UK Work Location: Pune, Kolkata, India

Component name: MBPT. MBPT is a capability to automate the process of product and tariff creation (for certain types) and price update. It is a part of BT's Antillia Billing System primarily based on RBM. Using MBPT capability if once the configurations are made on Billing the future product configuration related changes or price update can take place via PMF route (automated).

Technology: Oracle 11g PL/SQL, Unix

Role: Application developer (Development, Impact Analysis, Production Validation, Testing)

Responsibilities:

Creation of Low Level Design

SQL/PLSQL Coding in Oracle11G environment.

Unit Testing, support for SIT, UAT

Code version control with Subversion (SVN)

Preparing auto deployment Installer and Release Notes.

Designation: Application Developer/ SoftwareDeveloper

Feb 2015 - Feb 2016: Turk Telekom RBM Pilot Project

Client: Turk Telecom, Turkey

Work Location: Ankara, Kolkata, Turkey

Türk Telekom is the formerly state-owned Turkish telecommunications company. In November 2005, it was privatized to Oger Telecom. Turk Telekom group provides integrated telecommunication services from PSTN, GSM to wide-band Internet with its network substructure covering the whole country, the group's companies offer a wide range of services to personal and corporate customers. Our Project Scope is to design and develop the functionality to switch-over from their Legacy Billing Systems to Standardized RBM 5.3.7 Billing Application.

Technology: Java, Oracle 11g PL/SQL, Unix, Weblogic

Role: Application developer (Development, Maintenance, Impact Analysis, Production Validation, Testing)

Responsibilities:

Creation of Low Level Design and Client Manuals Java Coding, Code enhancement. SQL/PLSQL Coding in Oracle11G environment. Unit Testing, support for SIT, UAT and Live Issues. Test specs/Test results review. Code version control with Subversion (SVN)

Preparing auto deployment Installer and Release Notes.

Designation: Application Developer / Software Engineer

Oct 2014 - Feb 2015: EWMP Prospicio OR New

Client: British Telecommunications, UK

Work Location: Kolkata, India

This was an ASM project. Here support related jobs were performed like issue raise, live status monitoring, deployment of

deliverables etc.

Technology: Oracle 11g, Unix, Bridge Clarify

Role: Live issue handling, Live status monitoring, client handling, Deployments etc.

Designation: Application Support & Maintanance

Brotherzdesk.com as Web Developer

Nov 2013 to Apr 2014

Technology: HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, Photoshop, ASP.NET, SQL Server

Role: Application developer (Design, Development, Maintenance)

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from West Bengal University of Technology (WBUT) in 2013

PG: M.Tech (Computers) from Birla Institute of Technology and Science (BITS), Pilani in 2022

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Windows family, UNIX (Solaris),Linux	
Java, Oracle PL-SQL, UNIX	
HTML	
CSS, JavaScript ,Oracle 11g	
Toad, Eclipse, SQL Developer	

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=94a65a953bf0390bbd4dd8ab4eefbd820c0f5f544b475d405642420d555...

Edit plus, SOAP UI , FileZilla	
WinSCP, win merge, Tortoise SVN	
RBM 5.3.8, Weblogic Server 11g	
SOAP web service	
Hibernet, J2EE, mutlithreading	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			
Bengali	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: Antillia Billing Development Client: British Telecommunications Nature of Employment: Full Time Project Location: Kolkata

Role: Programmer

Team Size: 10 Skill Used: PLSQL, Java, Unix Shell Scripting, Filezilla, Tortoise SVN,

Duration: Oct 2017 - Till Date

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role Description: Creation of Low Level Design SQL/PLSQL Coding in Oracle11G environment.

Unit Testing, support for SIT, UAT

Code version control with Subversion (SVN)

Preparing auto deployment Installer and Release Notes.

Project Details: Its a Billing Engine. Product Tariff Prices are configured into this application. Antillia Billing System primarily based on RBM. Using MBPT capability if once the configurations are made on Billing the future product configuration related changes or price update can take place via PMF route (automated).

Affirmative Action

Countries: United Kingdom

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary Employment Status: Full time